到了
There it is!
[法语]黄金之谷…
Val d'or…
黄金峡谷
the valley of gold.
法国人不出现怎么办
What if the french don't show?
哦 他们会出现
Oh, they'll show.
只不过姗姗来迟
They'll just be fashionably late.
陛下 您看
Your majesty, look!
他们来了
There they are.
驻足
Au pas!
您有何打算
What's the plan?
我单枪匹马过去会他们的国王
I was to ride down alone and meet the king.
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
万一他们要诱您过去 加害于您怎么办？
What if they mean to lure you down there to kill you?
你们所有人
All of you!
都要视死如归
On pain of death!
留守在此
Stay!
国王驾到
The king!
表兄
Cousin.
[法语]欢迎来到法国
Bienvenue en france.
您先请
After you.
[法语]哦 不
Mais non.
还是您先请
After you.
你觉得我的胡子如何
How do you like my beard?
看起来像法国人 您知道吗
You almost look french, you know?
各位注意 各位注意
Hear ye! Hear ye!
我 亨利 以上帝之名
I, henry, by the grace of god,
身为英格兰 爱尔兰 及法国的国王 在此…
king of england, ireland and france, do hereby-
停
stop.
有您在此 我无法冠此头衔 有张冠李戴之嫌
I cannot be that while you are here, for I would be a liar.
此次会议中 我只是英格兰国王亨利
During this summit I am simply henry, king of england.
[法语]为此我深表感激
J'apprie orment.
而我 则是
And I am just…
法国及勃艮第的国王 弗朗西斯
franis, king of france and burgundy.
两位陛下 恳求您们手按圣经
Your majesties, may I ask you each to place a hand upon the holy bible,
在上帝以及聚集在此的诸位王公贵族面前发誓
and swear before god and these princes and lords here gathered,
你们将真诚而圣洁的爱戴对方
that you will be true, virtuous, and loving to each other.
我发誓
I so swear.
[法语]我也是
Moi aussi.
我也发誓
I swear too.
玛丽公主
Princess mary,
请允许我想您介绍亨利-菲利普王子 也就是您未来的丈夫
may I introduce prince henri philippe, your future husband.
- 你就是法国的皇太子？- [法语]是的
- Are you the dauphin of france? - Oui.
那我要吻你
Then I want to kiss you.
[法语]妈妈 妈妈
Maman! Maman!
[法语]老天
Mon dieu!
玛丽
Mary.
我也要弄这么个玩意
I have got to get one of these.
你觉得这个幻影之宫如何
The palace of illusions. What do you think?
让人难以置信 陛下
It's incredible, your majesty.
不过是涂漆的帆布
It's only painted canvas.
但酒是真的
But real wine!
查尔斯 别喝太多
Don't drink too much of it charles!
我为您准备了一份礼物
And now I have a gift for you.
您让我无颜以对 皇兄
You embarrass me, brother.
哦 不
Oh no.
我所能回赠您的只有这块馅饼
And all I can give you in return is this pastry.
[法语]非常有趣
Tramusant.
你在想什么 查尔斯
What are you thinking, charles?
我在想 既然我来到贵地
I'm thinking that, while I'm here,
就应该入乡随俗
I should behave like the king of france.
也就是说？
Which means?
也就是说…
Which means…
我也应该溜入伊甸园 欣然的招蜂引蝶
I shall slip readily into the gardens of others and drink water from many fountains.
看见那边的年轻女士了吗
Do you see that young woman over there?
身着紫色和金色礼服的那位
Dressed in purple and gold?
是的
Yes.
她名叫玛丽-博林
Her name is mary boleyn,
是你们大使的女儿
the daughter of your ambassador,
旁边是她的姐姐安
with her sister anne.
我称玛丽为英国母驴 经常被我骑在跨下
I call mary my english mare because I ride her so often.
啊 先生们
Ah!Gentlemen.
先生
Monsieur.
父亲
Papa.
亨利国王今天注意到你
King henry noticed you today.
他想见你
He wants to see you.
等等
Wait!
我要告诉安
I must go and tell anne.
安
Anne.
国王陛下…
The king…
啦哩…啦哩…啦哩啦勒
Lo li lo lay lo li lo lay.
飞鹰盘旋 夺走了我的少女
the falcon hath borne my maid away.
你叫什么名字 小伙子
what's your name, boy?
托马斯·塔利斯 殿下
Thomas tallis, your majesty.
塔利斯
Tallis.
好嗓子
Good voice.
我要封赏你的歌
Take a sovereign for your song.
感谢您 陛下
Thank you, your majesty.
啊 博林
Ah, boleyn.
白金汉有什么动静
What of buckingham?
他在我面前公然辱骂主教您
In my presence he has railed against your eminence,
说您是一个巫师 一个皮条客
calling you a necromancer, a pimp,
指责您利用邪恶的手段留住国王对您的欢心
accusing you of using evil ways to maintain your hold over the king.
关于国王 白金汉说了什么
And what did lord buckingham say about the king?
他跟我说 他更有资格继承王位
He told me he has a greater claim to the throne,
说陛下从无继位的资格
and that as his majesty has no male heirs,
将来也非名正言顺 还说他白金汉将要夺取王位
and will have none, that he, buckingham, will succeed to the throne.
但是 他还曾经说过
But he also told me once.
要加快事态的发展
that he has considered bringing that eventuality forward more quickly.
以什么方式？
In what way?
刺杀国王陛下
By assassinating his majesty.
你能告诉我 做得很好
You did well to come to me.
但我必须警告你 不要告诉任何人
But I must warn you, say nothing of this to anyone.
精彩
Bravo.
您看见了吗 皇兄
You see that, brother?
大多数方面 我们法国人都胜过你们
In most things, we french excel you.
我们有最出色的画家 音乐家和诗人
We have the greatest painters, the greatest musicians and the greatest poets.
不得不提的是 大多数还住在我的宫廷 真是上帝的恩赐
Most of whom, by the way, live at my court, dieu merci.
最杰出的哲学家 工程师 建筑师
The greatest philosophical minds, engineers, architects.
当然 我们还有最美的女人
And of course, we have the most beautiful women.
您无法否认 是不是
You won't deny that, will you?
连我们的摔跤手都好过你们的
Even our wrestlers are better than yours!
您确定？
Are you sure?
什么？
What?
我说您确定？
I said are you sure?
确定你们所有的摔跤手都好过我们的？
All your wrestlers are better than mine?
您想证明一下吗
Do you want to prove it?
您的意思是？
What are you suggesting?
我要挑战您比赛摔跤 皇兄
I am challenging you to a wrestling match, brother.
不 大卫
Non, david.
您是个懦夫
You're a coward.
[法语]去你的
Merde!
我以法国的荣誉为注
French honour is at stake.
接受您的挑战
I accept your challenge.
[法语]我很乐意奉陪到底
Parce que tel est notre bon plaisir.
我们现在就开始吧
Let's do it now.
男仆
Groom!
[法语]那好 就开始吧
Alors commence!
陛下…
Your majesty…
不
no.
两位陛下…
Your majesties…
先生们…
gentlemen…
比赛规则如下：
the rules are as follows:
首先将对手摔倒在地者 即为胜利者
The first man to throw his opponent to the ground shall be declared the winner.
您同意吗
Are you content?
同意
Yes.
比赛开始
Then fight on!
你打算下注在谁身上
What bet will you lay?
加油 亨利
Go, henry.
两个国王 两个皇后 还有一个笨蛋
2 kings, 2 queens and a fool.
谁是笨蛋？
Who's the fool?
还不知道 但这儿满屋子都是笨蛋
I don't know yet, but it's a full house.
加油 殿下
Come on, your majesty!
亨利会胜出
Henry's gonna win.
不管发生什么 他也不会赢
Whatever happens, he's not gonna win.
加油 亨利
Go, henry!
加油
Come on!
我要再来一局
I want a re-match!
我要再战一局
I want a re-match!!
您害怕了吗？
Are you afraid?
您害怕同我再战一局？
Are you afraid of a re-match?
您说我害怕？
Are you calling me afraid?
我有什么好怕的？
Of what am I supposed to be afraid?
怕我
Of me!
那就来吧
Let's have it then…
我不会签那份条约
I'm not going to sign the treaty!
我不会签那份条约 你去告诉他们
I'm not gonna sign it! Go and tell them!
- 那好 如果您真的… - 去 转告他们
- Alright if that's what - I said…go and tell them!
好了
Alright!
如果您想让全世界都认为英格兰国王
If you want the world to think that the king of england.
是如此善变 庸俗 脾气暴躁 言而无信的话
is easily changeable, shallow, intemperate, incapable of keeping his word.
那我一定会去转告他们
then of course, I will go tell them.
反正 我不过是您卑微的仆人
After all, I am merely your majesty's humble servant.
玛丽女士
Lady mary.
陛下
Your majesty.
我听闻你很多事情
I've heard a lot about you.
你在法国宫廷住了2年
You've been at the french court for 2 years.
告诉我…
Tell me…
你都学了什么法国礼仪？
what french graces have you learned?
陛下您允许吗？
With your majesty's permission?
允许
Granted.
在此 我恳求尊贵的英格兰国王陛下
And now I ask his gracious majesty, the king of england,
诚挚的在此万邦和平条约上
to also sign, in good faith, the treaty of universal…
签字
and perpetual peace.
伦敦 白厅宫
Whiteball palace london.
走开
Leave.
别再理那些法国佬
Forget about the french.
皇后的侄子已经被推举
The queen's nephew's been elected.
他不止是西班牙国王查理五世 还是圣罗马帝国的皇帝
Now he's not only charles v, the king of spain, he's also the holy roman emperor!
他的疆域辽阔 富甲天下
His dominions are vast, his wealth extraordinary.
却年轻的不过20岁
And he's only 20 years old.
你去安排和他在亚琛会面
You will make arrangements to visit him at aachen.
你亲自去
Personally.
相对于和法国人合作 还不如和他合作
It may suit us better to do business with him, than with the french.
遵命 陛下
Yes, majesty.
大人 托马斯-博林阁下到了
Sir thomas boleyn, your grace.
- 阁下大人 我… - 你对那场表演意下如何
- Your grace I - what did you think of that performance?
- 我… - 别装傻 你并不蠢
- I… - don't be stupid! You're not stupid.
就是国王的那场表演
The king's performance!
在首脑会议上的表演
At the summit!
你有什么感想？
How did it strike you?
我个人方面 很想看到
Personally, I would have wished to seen.
头顶英格兰皇冠者 是位更加伟大 更加神勇的男士
a greater more powerful man upon the throne of england.
单凭出面就可让法国人起立叩拜之人
Someone whose very presence would have made the french sit up and come to heel.
我有意愿也有手段 犹如撵死惹人厌恶的蜘蛛一般
I have the way and the means to crush the usurper of my throne.
将那个夺我王位的篡位者退下台
as one would crush a revolting spider.
我要他悔于登入教堂继位
I will make him wish that he had entered the church after all.
要他领悟到自己该将国家的事物交给天生王者
and left the affairs of the state to those who are born to rule!
如果你背叛我 博林
If you betray me boleyn,
我会丢你的尸体喂狗
I'll feed your body to my dogs.
现在说说看…
Now…
你在这里听到什么风声
what have you discovered here?
确凿的消息证明…
I have it on good authority…
白金汉公爵正在招兵买马
that the duke of buckingham is raising an army.
说是为了在他不受欢迎的威尔士郡巡游而防身
He says it's to protect him while he tours his welsh estates where he's not popular.
他还借了大量的款项
He's also been borrowing large sums of money.
白金汉
Buckingham.
以新年之名 邀他入宫
Invite him to court, for the new year.
但不要打草惊蛇
But don't say anything to alarm him.
你的孩子们可好
How are your children?
他们都很好 感谢您的关心 陛下
They're well, thank you, your majesty.
我鼓励他们学习
I encourage them all at their studies.
包括女孩子们
Even the girls.
果然是理想主义者
Always the idealist.
我想着 总有一天
At some point, I imagine,
女孩受教育会成为毫不稀奇
it will be considered ordinary enough,
十分正常的一件事
and nothing strange for a girl to be educated.
我收到件礼物
I've received a gift.
乌尔比诺公爵送的
From the duke of urbino.
是本叫「君王论」的书 作者是佛罗伦萨的尼可洛-马基雅维里
It's a book called the prince, by a florentine, niccolo machiavelli.
我知道这本书
Yes I know it.
是讲述政治时机的书
It's about political opportunity.
的确…
It's true…
跟你的书「乌托邦」不一样
it's not like your book, utopia.
没有你的那么…
It's less…
乌托邦
utopian.
不过他倒是提出了个重要的问题
Nevertheless he asks an important question.
身为国王关键在于受人敬畏呢…
whether it is better for a king to be feared…
还是受人爱戴
or loved.
白金汉想杀我
Buckingham is going to try and kill me.
主教阁下
Your eminence.
布朗特夫人
Lady blount.
到产期了？
You are full term?
快了
In a little while.
你还好吧？
Are you well?
如您所想
As can be expected.
国王陛下让您带口信了吗？
Have you some message from his majesty?
不 没有
No. None.
不过你丈夫倒是有
But from your husband.
我丈夫？
My husband?
是的 我跟他谈过
Yes, I have spoken to him.
他觉得…
He finds that he is…
可以接受你的状况
reconciled to your condition.
他不会把我送进修道院？
Then he won't send me to a nunnery?
他将被赐伯爵头衔 并有领地
He will be made an earl and be given estates.
那么我的孩子？
And my child?
是否认这个孩子只有国王本人能决定
That is for the king to decide whether he will recognize the child.
抱歉我无法给你更多安慰
I'm afraid I can offer you no more comfort than that.
您能向国王转达我对他的爱吗？
Will you tell the king of my love for him?
白金汉领地 潘雪斯特
Buckingbam's Estate Pensburst.
领主
My lord.
我在此宣誓效忠您及您的家族
I here by pledge my allegiance to you and your house.
发誓永远辅助您 至死不渝
and do swear to serve you, even unto death.
从心底感谢你
We thank you from the bottom of our heart.
事成之后 你们的忠诚将得到丰厚的
And in due course, you will find your loyalties richly.
恰当的奖赏
and properly rewarded.
我想应该告诉你
I thought I should tell you.
我被派去会见 神圣罗马帝国的新任皇帝
I am being sent to meet the new holy roman emperor.
国王令我拟一份新条约
The king has asked me to draw up a new treaty,
联合两国对抗法国
uniting us against the french.
- 您一定很失望 - 我很现实
- You must be very disappointed. - I am very realistic.
那我可失望了
Then I am disappointed.
- 我们的梦想十分不切实际 - 也许如此
- Our dreams were very unrealistic. - Maybe so.
但我会坚持下去
But I will continue to dream them.
纵使我要独自前行
even if I am alone in doing so.
恐怕陛下不再…
I fear his majesty no longer…
像以前一般信任我 在乎我了
trusts or cares for me as he once did.
托马斯 听我一句话
Thomas, let me give you a little advice.
想要保有君王的宠爱 必须做的事情就是
If you want to keep the love of a prince, this is what you must do:
做好把你在这世上最珍视的东西 献给他的准备
You must be prepared to give him the thing you most care for in all the world.
我最珍视的是我的气节
The thing I care for most is my integrity.
主教阁下您最珍视什么？
What is it you care for most in the world, your eminence?
为伟大的白金汉公爵让路
Make way for the great duke of buckingham!
诺福克公爵大人到
His grace, the duke of norfolk.
大人
Your grace.
望陛下笑纳这简陋的新年礼物
I hope your majesty will accept this humble gift for the new year.
我夫妇十分感谢大人
We are very grateful to your grace.
你的慷慨使我感激难言 一如既往
Your generosity overwhelms me. As always.
躺下
Lie down.
叫仆人来
Get some minions.
白金汉公爵大人到
His grace, the duke of buckingham.
大人
Your grace.
陛下
Your majesty.
有句子… 雕刻在上面
It…has some words engraved on it.
拿过来
Give it to me.
「致此谦恭 真挚之心」
"With humble, true heart".
十分感激大人 你的话让我深受感动
Your grace overwhelms me. Your words touch me.
这句话就是最好的礼物
They are the greatest gift.
比任何财富更有价值
Greater than any riches.
用力推
Push.
吸气
Breathe.
就出来了
It's coming.
「致此谦恭 真挚之心」
"With true and humble heart."
在那儿
There!
大人请停下
Hold your grace!
做什么？
What do you want?
大人涉嫌叛国 需受拘捕
Your grace is arrested on suspicion of treason.
奉国王之命 我要将您押送高塔
I am ordered by the king's majesty to take you to the tower.
- 听我一句劝 先生们 让我们过去 - 决不
- You take my advice, gentlemen, you let us pass. - By no means.
若您身边任何一位随从反抗陛下仆从
And if any of your men should strike against his majesty's servants.
即便是尽职之举
in pursuit of their duties.
均会被认为叛国 大人您应当清楚
that is treason too, as your grace should know.
大人？
Your grace?
你们初出茅庐
You are only new men.
你们什么都不懂
You don't know anything.
如果我被控告叛国
If I'm accused of treason,
审判我的会是我自己的同僚 而不是那屠夫的走狗
I should be judged by a jury of my peers, not by the dogs of butchers.
英格兰没有一个王公贵族敢判我有罪
There's no lord in england who'll ever find against me!
列队包围
Form them up!
我设立了由高级官员组成的法庭 审判白金汉的案子
I have instituted a court of high steward to judge buckingham's case.
20名贵族将被指派上法庭
20 peers will be appointed to the court.
诺福克将是第一个
Norfolk will be first among them.
- 陛下 我能否… - 什么？
- Your majesty, if I may… - what?
我相信判公爵的叛国罪会带来危险
I believe it could be dangerous to find the duke guilty of treason.
- 就算他真有罪？- 就算他真有罪
- Even if he is? - Even if he is.
另一方面 他可以被判轻一些的罪
On the other hand, he could be found guilty of some lesser offence.
处以大量罚金 驱逐出庭
heavily fined and banished from court.
这样他将会受尽羞辱
In that way he would be disgraced.
但他的友人同盟 就找不到反抗您的理由了
but his friends and allies would have little cause or occasion to rise against you.
这会是最好的结果？
And that would be the best outcome?
我相信 是的
I believe it would, yes.
你会负责保证法庭做出此判决？
And you would see to it that the court came to that decision?
我对此信心十足
I have every confidence.
我对阁下你也是
As I have in your eminence.
设立法庭的是沃尔西 领导法庭的是诺福克
Wolsey will set up the court. Norfolk will head it.
我要你去提醒这位大人他的职责
I want you to remind his grace of his responsibilities.
40-30 勇攀高峰啊 先生们 上啊
40-30! Chase to full, gentlemen.Bull!
玛利？
Mary?
国王晚上还有召见你吗？
Does the king still call for you at night?
没有了 爸爸
No papa.
即便国王是你的教父 你走上前时…
Even though the king is your godfather when you approach him…
- 大人 - 什么事？
- your grace. - What do you want?
只是传达陛下的关爱
Only to pass on his majesty's love.
他对于您在白金汉大人审讯中 挺身而出独当一面表示感谢
He appreciates the role you will play at my lord buckingham's trial.
也感谢您平时对陛下的关心
And for all the care you have for his majesty's well being.
他还要给您这个
He also sends you this.
这是我父亲的戒指
This is my father's ring.
他是被陛下的父亲处死的 你知道吗？
He was executed by his majesty's father, did you know that?
陛下觉得您应该会愿意戴上它
His majesty thought you might like to wear it.
- 这是令郎？- 是的
- Is this your son? - Yes it is.
他正要去见他的教父 也就是国王陛下
He is going to be received by his godfather. The king.
大人应该多多关心您的继承人
Your grace should have a care for his inheritance.
如果您的举动使得他丧失
It would be terrible, for example, if some action of yours.
父亲 头衔以及戒指的话 那就太可惜了
were to deprive him of a father, a title and a ring.
告辞了 大人
Your grace.
大人被控叛国
Your grace has been accused of treason.
及预谋和策划刺杀国王陛下
and of imagining and plotting the death of the king's majesty.
本庭的高级官员 在审查所有相关控诉您的证据之后…
This court of high steward, after reviewing all the evidence against your grace…
我们判定大人…
finds your grace…
所有罪名成立
guilty of the charges against you.
不
No.
因此…
And so…
根据陛下旨意 处大人以死刑
sentences your grace to death, at his majesty's pleasure.
都是你搞的鬼
This is your doing!
你这屠夫的走狗
You butcher's dog!
全是… 你搞的鬼
It's all…your doing!
杂种
Bastards!
好啊
Yes!
上帝保佑您 先生
God bless you, sir.
拿上这个 大人
Take this your grace.
您原谅我吗？
Do you forgive me?
大人请趴下
Your grace must lie down.
您伸开双臂 我便动手
When you stretch out your arms, I will strike!
请伸开双臂
Stretch out your arms.
我有儿子了
I have a son.
感谢上帝
Thank god.
快点 懦夫
Come on you coward.
我有儿子了
I have a son!
哈 哈
Ha!Ha!
我有儿子了 上帝 听到了吗？
I have a son, god! Can you hear me?
我有儿子了
I have a son!
真该为了如此幸事恭喜陛下
Your majesty is to be congratulated on such a happy event.
谢谢 主教阁下
Thank you, your eminence.
夫人在楼上
The lady is upstairs.
- 亨利 恭喜 - 谢谢 查尔斯
- Henry, congratulations. - Thank you charles.
我就知道不是我的错
I always knew it wasn't my fault.
当然
No.
陛下决定认下他的儿子
His majesty has decided to recognize his son.
暂赐名亨利-菲茨罗伊
He will be known for the present as henry fitzroy.
他将在达翰姆郡拥有自己的官邸
He will have his own establishment at durham house,
还有一名牧师 一名将领以及扈从 与之身份地位相符
with a chaplain, officer and a retinue befitting his station.
谢谢
Thank you.
你该写信向陛下致谢 我只是遵照他的吩咐
You should write and thank his majesty. I only do his bidding.
王后驾到 王后驾到
The queen! The queen!
敬我的儿子
To my son!
罗马 圣彼得大教堂
St. Peter's Basilica Rome.
你跟沃尔西有什么协议？
What was your deal with wolsey?
作为英格兰不与法国开战的回报
In return for england not going to war with france.
我向他承诺 法国将投他一票
I promised him the french vote.
事实上 沃尔西已经去了亚琛 面见新皇帝
The fact is, wolsey has gone to aachen to meet the new emperor.
很显然 他意图对你国毁约
He obviously means to break the treaty with your king.
这样一来…
In which case…
我方便无义务履行承诺了
we are no longer obliged to deliver our side of the bargain.
愿吾之圣人安息
Corpus domini nostri jesu christi.
无论如何 我们不要英国教皇 已经有过一个了
In any case, we don't want an english pope. We had one once.
一个疯子 再也不要了
He was insane. Never again.
教皇非意大利人不可 这是上帝的旨意
The pope must be an italian. That is god's will.
- 教皇宗座 您必须吞下 - 塞进去
- Your holiness must swallow it. - Push it!
仁慈的圣母 我向您祈祷 我恳求您
My lady, full of grace, I pray you, I beseech you.
我对您和您的圣子耶稣基督 献上我所有谦卑的爱
In all humility for the love I bear for you and for your son jesus christ.
我恳求您…
I pray you…
赐予我婴孩
give me a child.
一个男孩 让我孕育之处不再空虚
A son to fill my empty womb.
求您…
I beg you…
几周后 朝廷会从白厅搬出 迁移至汉普顿王宫
in a few weeks the court will quit whitehall for hampton court.
城中眼下汗热病肆虐
There's been an incident of the sweating sickness in the city.
你也知道国王对疾病多么惧怕
You know how afraid the king is of any illness.
国王怎么样了？
How is the king?
听说枢机主教奥尔西尼当选教皇 我很抱歉
I was sorry to hear of cardinal orsinI's election as pope.
你永远都在抱歉 摩尔
You are perpetually sorry, more.
我并不只是出于礼貌
I wasn't simply being polite.
是吗？
Oh, really?
当然
I was not.
只要教会中 这种明目张胆的腐败 还存在一天
As long as there is such blatant corruption in the church,
就会不断有追随者 加入那异教徒路德的队伍
that heretic luther will continue to gain followers.
我知道若是阁下您当选
I know that if your eminence had been elected,
您定会不知疲倦地净化教会 使之脱离邪恶之事
you would have worked tirelessly to cleanse the church of all its evil practices.
或许你视我过高 托马斯
Perhaps you think too highly of me, thomas.
你也许将整个人类种族都视得过高
Perhaps, you think too highly of the whole human race.
布朗特夫人
Lady blount.
摩尔先生
Mr. More.
王后驾到
The queen!
夫人
My lady.
王后到
The queen!
舅舅
Uncle.
安
Anne.
可爱的安
Sweet anne.
是 爸爸
Yes, papa.
知道为什么叫你来这儿？
You know why you are here?
不知道 爸爸
No, papa.
巴黎没人告诉我
In paris, no one explained.
好
Good.
这样更好
It's better that way.
发生什么事了？
What's happened?
陛下对他的法国盟友已然厌倦
His majesty is tiring of his french alliance.
似乎对你妹妹也已厌倦
It seems he is also tiring of your sister.
他不再邀请她上床了
He no longer invites her to his bed.
可怜的玛丽
Poor mary.
我们才可怜
Poor us!
她做他情人的时候 我们积聚了所有财富
When she was his mistress all our fortunes were made.
现在很可能将要失去了
Now most likely they will fall.
除非…
Unless…
就算他看上我一时 谁能保证他看上我一世？
even if he had me, who is to say he would keep me?
不只玛丽一个
It's not just mary.
人们说他所有的暧昧关系都不长久
They say that all his liaisons are soon over.
他摇摆不定 阴晴未卜
He blows hot, he blows cold.
也许你能想出什么方法 让他的兴趣更…
Perhaps you could imagine a way to keep his interest more…
长久？
prolonged?
我敢说你在法国学了不少吧？
I daresay you learned things in france?
怎样使他神魂颠倒
How to play his passions.
你蕴藏着危险而又让人深陷的东西
There's something deep and dangerous in you, anne.
你的双眼仿佛能勾人心魄
Those eyes of yours are like dark hooks for the soul.
你跟罗马皇帝的会面怎么样？
How was your meeting with the emperor?
不错
Good.
颇有收获
Productive.
他毫不掩饰对法国人的憎恶
He makes no secret of his antipathy for the french.
他想对法国开战
He wants to go to war with them.
十分急切想要与陛下结成同盟
and he is desperate for an alliance with your majesty.
作为同盟的回报呢？
And in return for our alliance?
对法国采取联合入侵
There will be a joint invasion of france.
颠覆弗朗西斯国王的政权
for the overthrow of king francis.
我便能登基
And I shall claim the crown.
再次真正成为英格兰 爱尔兰以及法兰西的王
and once more truly be king of england, ireland, and france,
就跟我祖先一样
just like my forefathers.
阁下你建造的宫殿是最华美的
Your eminence, has built the most beautiful palace.
谢谢 陛下
Thank you, your majesty.
很可能是英格兰最精美的房屋了
Probably the finest house in england.
我无之与其媲美
I have nothing to compare with it.
再没有比这更美的了
Nothing to show more fair.
陛下
Your majesty,
它是您的了
it is yours.
连同陈设？
With the furnishings?
快
Come on!